Verle G. Kaiser Papers 1932-1982
Washington State University Libraries: Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
Verle G. Kaiser Papers
1932-1982
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Terrell Library Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 527
Verle G. Kaiser
27 containers. 29 linear feet of shelf space.
Correspondence, papers on types of soils and their uses, newspaper clippings, material dealing with aspects of soil erosion in the Palouse area, field diaries of Kaiser, 1936-1976, and records of his activities in soil development projects in Colombia, Nicaragua, Honduras and Iran. Includes some of his personal records. Also, maps detailing the soils, crops, and erosion of soil in eastern Washington.
Verle G. Kaiser was born in 1911. In 1922 his family traveled west from North Dakota and settled on a dairy farm near Cheney, Washington. After graduating from high school, Mr. Kaiser attended Cheney State Normal School and the Washington State College at Pullman. In 1933 he graduated with a Bachelor of Science in agriculture, and in 1934 completed an engineering degree. Before and after his engineering studies he worked for the Soil Erosion Service. Subsequently, he worked as an agronomist a district conservationist, and an area conservationist in western Washington and northern Idaho. In 1955 he became the Agronomy specialist for Washington, Idaho, and Oregon.
Kaiser was best known for his expertise in conservation problems in the Palouse. His articles have appeared in Northwest Science and in Journal of Soil and Water Conservation; he also contributed to technical bulletins of the agricultural experiment stations in the Pacific Northwest. Mr. Kaiser's work for the soil conservation service has added to the technical guides and conservation handbooks for the Palouse area. Before and after his retirement in 1972, Mr. Kaiser undertook consulting assignments for the Development and Resources Corporation in Iran, Nicaragua and Columbia. Kaiser also campaigned to have the United States Department of Agriculture adjust its programs to meet the conservation needs of the Columbia Plateau region. Kaiser died in Spokane County, Washington, in 1982.
This collection consists of papers of soil scientist Verle G. Kaiser. It includes correspondence, papers on types of soils and their uses, newspaper clippings, material dealing with aspects of soil erosion in the Palouse area, field diaries of Kaiser, 1936-1976, audio recordings, and records of Kaiser's activities in soil development projects in Colombia, Nicaragua, Honduras and Iran. It also includes some of his personal records, and maps detailing the soils, crops, and erosion of soil in eastern Washington.
This collection is arranged in 13 series. The arrangement roughly follows that used by Mr. Kaiser, save that folders have been alphabetized within the various series. The subject filing system used by Kaiser is somewhat informal, with separate categories and series for materials that are not mutually exclusive, so related items and subjects may be found in multiple locations within the collection.
SERIES LIST
Series 1: Agriculture. Correspondence relating to crop planting techniques and soil conservation in the Northwest.
Series 2: Agronomy. Documents concerning specific types of soils, their conservation and uses, as well as reports on Agronomy Society meetings.
Series 3: Clippings. Articles from various Northwest newspapers regarding soil and forest conservation in the region, and meetings for that purpose.
Series 4: Correspondence. Letters between Verle Kaiser and various individuals, plus letters concerning specific agricultural and conservation projects.
Series 5: Erosion. Material dealing with various aspects of soil erosion in the Palouse area.
Series 6: Field Diaries. Verle Kaiser's diaries recording his activities in the field as a soil conservation agent between 1936 and 1976.
Series 7: International Projects. Correspondence and records of Mr. Kaiser's activities in soil conservation and development projects in Columbia, Nicaragua, Honduras, and Iran.
Series 8: Personal Interests and Activities. Personal papers, including convention meetings, speeches, and slide talks.
Series 9: Pacific Northwest. Information concerning soil conservation in the Northwest, types of plants that conserve the soil, and conservation meetings.
Series 10: The Palouse. Environmental and soil conservation studies of the Palouse area ranging from 1934 to the 1970's.
Series 11: Soil Conservation. Materials providing an overview of soil conservation and of the soil conservation service in the Northwest and nationwide, from the 1930s to the 1970s.
Series 12: Maps and Graphs. Most of these items detail the soils, crops, and erosion of soils of eastern Washington. The majority are printed maps, with Kaiser's manuscript annotations and added information.
Series 13: Audio Recordings. Audiocassette recordings of presentations, speeches, and narrations of published reports.
The papers of Verle G. Kaiser were donated to the Washington State University Libraries in 1982 (MS1982-47, MS1982-54, MS 1994-36) by members of his family.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Kaiser, Verle G., 1911-1982 --Archives
Soil conservation--Colombia; Soil conservation--Nicaragua; Soil conservation--Honduras; Soil conservation--Iran; Soil erosion -- Palouse Region (Idaho and Wash.)
Agriculture; International Relations; Washington (State); Idaho
- Agriculture, Series 1
  - A Comparison of Cropping Systems, Palouse, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Lesson in Farming, 1961; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A Lesson in Farming, 1961; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Address on Defense: A. Lars Nelson, 1951; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agenda for Farm Planning, Oakesdale, 1955; 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Bureau Policy, 1966-1967; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agricultural Conservation Handbook, 1963; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Development: "Federal Aid", 1967; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Information Bulletin No. 255, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Research Journal: "Seismology", 1967; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Agriculture Experiment Station of Nebraska, 1909; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Agriculture Experiment Station in Greece, Agronomy Journal, 1954; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Agriculture Lacks A Golden Orator....", 1965; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Agriculture/Soil Conservation in Washington, 1950-1969; 11 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alfalfa Seeding and Growth, 1963; 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Background on Farm and Food Prices", 1967; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Background on Our Nation's Agriculture", 1961; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Basic Terms and their Meaning, 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Before You Pass Up The Set-Aside", Farm Journal, 1978; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - California: Desert Agriculture, 1957; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - "Can Other Uses Be Made of Agricultural Excess Acres?", by R. Burnell Held, 1961; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Can Population Catch Up With Our Food Supply?" Farmers Journal, 1975; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Capability Units for Non-Irrigated Cropland of Eastern Washington, 1965; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Castor Bean Production, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Century of Agriculture in Charts and Tables, United States Department of Agriculture, 1866-1966", 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Columbia Basin Project: Relative Land Productivity and Income, 1956; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Columbia River Basin Area Agricultural Program: Summary Report, 1953; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Commercial Fertilizers on Range Land: Western Whitman County, 1944-1945; 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Communist China's Agriculture", 1959; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Comprehensive Review--Bibliography--Department of Agricultural Economics, 1961; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Conservation Legislation Sparked by 'Dust Bowl,'" by Marvin Jones, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Conservation Plan, Soil Conservation District, 1958; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Conservogram, 1982; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Contour and Field Strip Cropping, 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Contour Farming: Stripcropping, Terraces, 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, Department of Agriculture, 1941; 7 items. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, Department of Agriculture: Pacific Northwest, 1939, 1940, 1941; 18 items. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Are Department of Agriculture Technical Guides Too Complicated?, 1969; 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Cross-Wind Farming, 1967; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Cultivation of Soil in the Palouse, Ritzville, and Walla Walla, 1880-1950; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Desert Agriculture, 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Development and Resources Corporation Newsletter, 1969; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Drainage: State Engineering Handbook, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Dryland Agriculture, 1955; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Eastern Washington, 1965; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Technical Advisory Committee, 1978; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Effect of Soils and Fertilizers, Reynolds Creek Watershed, 1963, 1965; 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Engineering Handbook for Work Unit Staffs, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Environmental Crisis Down On The Farm, by James Risser Des Moines Register, 1978; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Excerpts from United States Department of Agriculture Bulletin, 1946; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Excerpts: Fact Book, Department of Agriculture, 1963; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Farm and Ranch Planning Committee Meeting, Soil Conservation Planning, 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Farm Management Advisory Service, 1974, 1976; 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Planning, 1941, 1945, 1946; 21 items. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Farm Planning, Land Use Symbols, 1937; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Farm Planning Practices, l978, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Fertilizer Needs of Wheat, Columbia Basin Dryland of Oregon, 1961; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Food and Agriculture, A Program for the 1960's, 1962; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Food and Agriculture Shortage Predicted and Cafeteria Donated, near Bogota, Columbia, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - "Food Spending versus Food Costs", 1966; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Generalized Plan for Land Treatment, Pullman, 1967; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Glossary of Terms Used in Soil Conservation, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Grasses, Legumes and Conservation Methods for Saline-Alkali Land, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Growing Sweet Clover in Latah County, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Growth of Safflower, Flax, Sesame, Rye, Grain Sorghum, 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Guidelines for Complying With Agricultural Act of 1970, 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Harvest in the United States: Crop Production and Nutrient Removal, 1965; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - How to Use Rice Hulls as an Aid in Planting Grasses, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Improved Procedures for Conservation, 1951; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Instruction Manual: Dr. Thornwaite's Cropmeter, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Joint Utah-Idaho Conservation Dryland Farming Guide, 1955; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - La Grande, Oregon, Grass Industry, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Land Capability Classification--Agricultural Handbook 210, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Land Economics, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - "Land of Plenty"--Farm Equipment Institute, 1950; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Leaf Analyses, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Lespedeza Culture and Utilization, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - "Lessons From A Foreign Agriculture," Verle Kaiser, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Memos on Land Capability Classification, 1962-1965; 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Memos on Land Capability Classification, 1940-1945; 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1965-1966; 9 items. (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, undated; 11 items. (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Movement of Soil During Tillage Operations, 1942; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Mulch Tillage in Modern Farming, Number 554, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - National Association of Conservation Districts
    - Newsletters, 1978, 1979, 1981; 40 items. (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Catalogue of Soil and Water Conservation Practices, 1952; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Catalogue of Practices and Measures Used in Soil and Water Conservation, 1959; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Catalogue of Practices and Measures Used in Soil and Water Conservation, 1965; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Nation's First Watershed Project: Dr. Hugh Hammond Bennett, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Nature of the Influence of Crop Residues, 1955-1970; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Notes on Conservation Program, Kuhn Brothers, Pomeroy, Washington, 1960; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - "No-Till Farming Cuts Erosion," by Fred Watter, undated; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - News, Organization of Professional Employees, United States Department of Agriculture, 1982; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Northwest Native Grasses: Pasture and Range Plants, 1956; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Pictures of Dryland Farming, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Policy and Procedure for Developing a National Inventory of Soil and Water Conservation Needs, 1957; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - "Poverty or Conservation--Your National Problem" Jay N. Darling, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Practice Specifications for Agricultural Conservation, State of Washington, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - "Proceedings of the Agricultural Conference on Land and Water Resources", 1969; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - "Rangeland Drill Seeding versus Conventional Drill on Poor Condition Rangeland", 1967; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Report on Rangeland Drill Trials, 1967; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Rothamsted--British Agricultural Research, 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - "Sainfoin: New Bloat-Free Legume for Range?", 1970; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Selection of Counties for 1964-1965 Conversion Program, 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Soil and Water Conservation for Dryfarm Lands of Columbia River Basin, Verle Kaiser, 1985; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Soil and Water Conservation Glossary, 1952; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Soil and Water Conservation Plan, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Soil and Water Conservation, 1958; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Soil and Water Conservation - Grangeville, Idaho, 1962; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Soil and Water Conservation, 1963; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Soil Conservation - Grassed Waterways, 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Soil Conservation Service and Field Offices, 1954; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Soil Conservation Service, Spokane, 1965; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Soil Conservation Abroad, Edward H. Graham, 1964; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Soil Erosion and Land Use Capabilities--Alternative Treatments, Eastern Washington, 1966; 74 items. (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Some Facts About Dryland Agriculture and Soil and Water Conservation in eastern Washington, 1963; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Soviet Agriculture Today, 1963; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - "Special Areas Soil Conservation Act of 1980", 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Stabilizing Sand Dunes on the Pacific Coast with Woody Plants, 1962; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Staff Meeting, Development and Resources Corporation, New York, 1969; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - State Technical Standards and Specifications for Conservation Cropping Systems, 1964; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - "Stripcropping on Eastern Oregon Grainlands," Thomas I. Wilson, 1958; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Suggestions for Control of the Pea Aphid, 1938; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Summary of Changes from the "Soil and Water Conservation Law" to the current "Conservation District Law", 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Technical Notes, Department of Agriculture, 1966; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Technical Standards and Specifications--Conservation Weed Control, 1962; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Temperature Relations to Time of Maturity of Vegetable Crops, 1952; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - "Testing New Range Plants," John L. Schwendiman, 1958; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - "The AGRI System" Computerized Irrigation Study, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - "The Atom and Nuclear Weapons", 1966; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - "The Big Turn," Farm Journal, 1967; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - The Early Detection of Crop Damage Through X-Ray, 1969; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - The Effect of Tillage Methods Upon Yield and Quality of Cereals in Dry-Land Areas, 1937; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - The Family Farm in American Agriculture, 1963; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - The Growing of Crysantheums Under Electric Lights, 1963; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - The Look of our Land: an Airphoto Atlas, 1970; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - The Problems of Bromus Tectorum and its Effect on Farmland, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - The Professional Worker in Agriculture, 1967; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - "The Unfinished Job," J.C. Dykes, 1965; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - "The Wheat Shortage is Here," Karl Hobson, 1966; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Tillage of Sweetclover Under Dryland Conditions, 1962; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Top Ten Crops in the United States, 1965; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - "Toward a Healthier Agriculture,", 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Two-Four D and Weed Control, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Undesirable Grasses, 1956; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - United States Department of Agriculture
    - Report on Water and Land, John Day Basin, 1961; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - SCS Engineering and Watershed Planning Units, 1961; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - SCS Extension Farm Plan, Whitman County, undated; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - Copy of Interior Department Yearbook, 1971; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - SCS Opportunities for Outdoor Recreation, 1971; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - SCS Practice Specifications, 1949, 1964; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Program News, 1970; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - SCS, Remarks by Verle G. Kaiser, Spokane, 1963; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Information about Set-Aside Acreage, 1971; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - Soil Conservation Service, 1972; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - SCS in Idaho, Conservation Cropping, 1963; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - SCS in Idaho, Conservation Cropping, 1964; 12 items. (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - SCS in Idaho, Conservation Cropping, Contour Farming, undated; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - SCS in Idaho, Conservation Cropping, Uphill Plowing, 1964; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - SCS in Idaho, Conservation Cropping, Weed Control, 1964; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - SCS Pacific Region, Speakers' Guide, 1949; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - SCS Recreation Costs, undated; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - SCS Soil Survey Interpretations, 1964; 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - SCS Spokane, Washington, 1966; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - SCS Washington, D.C., 1963; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - Statistical Report, Annual, 1964; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 168)
    - "You and the U.S.D.A.", undated; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 169)
    - Verle G. Kaiser's Notes on Soil Conservation, 1961; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 170)
    - Water for Western Federal Irrigation Projects, undated; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 171)
    - Water pollution, undated; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 172)
    - Wheat Referendum of 1963, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 173)
    - "Who's Tops in the Farmer's Brain Trust?", undated; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 174)
    - William A. Jump's Retirement, 1948; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 175)
    - World Food Forum, 1962; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 176)
- Agronomy, Series 2
  - "A Forward Look At Soil Use in the United States", 1967; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - A Series by the American Society of Agronomy, "Food for Peace", 1963; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 178)
  - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service Annual Report, 1970; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 179)
  - Agronomy Functional Inspection, Western Washington, 1963; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - Annual Agronomy Conference and Grass School, 1939; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - Annual Agronomy Conference and Grass School, 1940; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - Annual Agronomy Reports, 1938-1940; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 183)
  - Annual Progress Report for Field Test, 1939; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 184)
  - Christian Ethics of the Soil Conservationist, 1955; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 185)
  - Classification of Washington Soils, 1966; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 186)
  - Committee Reports of the Agronomy Range Section Meeting, Pullman, 1936; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 187)
  - Conservation Crop Rotations, 1958; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 188)
  - Description of Marengo Soils, undated; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 189)
  - Descriptive Legends for Soil Surveys, 1965; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 190)
  - EROS Data Center, South Dakota, undated; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 191)
  - Extent of Different Land Capabilities, eastern Washington, 1970; 8 items. (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - Formative Elements for Names of Great Groups and Subgroups in Soils, undated; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 193)
  - Generalized Plan for Land Treatment, Pullman, 1967; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 194)
  - "Grasses, Legumes, and Cultural Methods for Improving Pasture Production", 1959; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 195)
  - Guide for the Tectural Classification of Clay, 1950; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 196)
  - Index of Soil Series in Subgroups, undated; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 197)
  - Introduction to the Classification System of the United States and Procedures in Soil Mapping, 1967; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 198)
  - Journal--Soil Science, 1963; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 199)
  - Kettle-Stevens Soil Conservation District, Colville, Washington: History, 1955; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 200)
  - Lind Experiment Station Data: 1969-1970, 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 201)
  - Logic in Soil Survey Work, undated; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 202)
  - Long-Range Plan for Weed-Control, undated; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 203)
  - "Loss of Northern China", 1959; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 204)
  - Memorandums: Soils and Soil Surveys, 1960; 8 items. (Box 3, Folder 205)
  - MLRA Technical Guides, Oregon, 1961-1962; 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 206)
  - Names of Orders, Suborders, and Great Groups of the New System of Soil Classification, 1965; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 207)
  - NASC--A Voice for Local Responsibility in Resource Development, 1961; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 208)
  - National and State Memos on Soil Mapping and Classification, 1954-1956; 14 items. (Box 3, Folder 209)
  - National and State Memos on Soil Mapping and Classification, 1967-1971; 25 items. (Box 3, Folder 210)
  - National Association of Soil Conservation Districts, Annual Report, New Orleans Convention, 1954; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 211)
  - North Fork Palouse Soil Conservation District, Soils, Soil Survey Maps, 1949, 1960; 31 items. (Box 3, Folder 212)
  - Northern Idaho Area, 1939-1940; 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 213)
  - "Our Land and its Care," Washington, D.C., undated; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 214)
  - Pine Creek Soil Conservation District Annual Report, 1966; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 215)
  - "Potentially Arable Soils of the World and Critical Measures for their Use," USDA, undated; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 216)